Witch!
Forgive me, I have to do this.
Witch! Witch!
Witch!
I tried to warn them,
but they wouldn't listen.
- I tried to save them.
- Witch!
- Oh shit, thanks, I didn't see that.
- Neither did I.
People say, "seeing is believing"
But for me that's not entirely true.
I lost my sight when I was 5 years old.
those memories of what I have seen...
had faded so much that I doubt
I'd even recognize myself anymore.
Now I see using my other senses.
I can smell the rain before it drops.
But I can't watch it fall.
I can feel the sun on my face.
But I can't see it rise or set.
I want to see the world like everyone else,
to see the sun, the rain, the music.
I bet the music looks beautiful.
Thank you, thank you, thank you.
It's nice, tastes good.
- Happy Birthday.
- Thank you.
- Good evening, Miss Wells.
- Hi, Miguel.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
- Lilies.
- Came just this morning.
I sod it up for roses, but uh...
you're the first one that's noticed.
Nervous about tomorrow?
No.
Actually, I have never been
so scared in my entire life.
Listen, the night before
my mother's surgery,
she drank two glasses of sherry.
- Steady as a rock the next day.
- Thank you.
- Good night.
This is Dr. Haskins's office calling from County General,
your procedure is still on schedule for tomorrow.
Be sure to arrive at the hospital 4 hours early
for pre-op. Thank you.
Hi sweetie, it's your sister,
My flight get's in at 5 am...
The whole crew's got a layover, so I'll find
someone who'll give me a ride straight to hospital.
I love you, Sydney,
can't wait to see you. Bye.
12:10 am.
- Hello?
- Shhh...
My (?), she's on from twelve to six
and... well, she takes away my M & M's,
if I get out of bed.
I'm Alicia, I'm holding out my hand to shake.
Oh, I'm Sydney.
I know, Sydney Wells,
I uh... kind a read your chart.
You had a cornea transfer.
- How old are you?
- Nine and a half.
It's just like... well, golf ball
thingies inside my head.
It makes me sick,
so I can't even ride my bike,
You see, the doctors
are trying to get it out.
- When will you get to see?
- Pretty soon, I think.
Good, I'll come back,
then you... can take a look at me.
OK. Bye, nice to meet you.
Bye.
I'm starting to lose the
feeling in my fingers.
Yeah, me too.
OK...
- Would you excuse me?
- Yes, Sir.
Alright.
- All right, Sydney, now I'll take the bandages off.
- OK.
- You ready?
- Yeah.
That's one.
That's two.
OK... now, I'm gonna help you...
open your eyes, very slowly.
- Ok.
Slowly, slowly, slowly.
Come on, okay.
Good... now tell me what you see.
I can't uh...
I'm gonna hold up my hand...
and I want you to tell me,
how many fingers I have up, ok?
- Those are fingers?
- Yes, they are.
Alright, here we go.
- All of them?
- Yes... very good.
- Sydney.
- Yeah.
I want you to try and reach out
and grab my hand... OK.
It's okay, it’s okay, not everybody
can do this right away, it's okay.
- It burns a little.
- Is that normal?
Yeah, it's perfectly normal.
- Very good.
- Thank you.
Am I how you pictured it?
I don't know.
You're really blurry.
- I wish mom and dad were here to see this.
- Yeah...
I think I wanted this more than you, Sydney.
Helen, you were twelve...
I've waited for this for fifteen years.
I thought, I'd feel a sense of uh...
- It's really freaky...
- It's not your fault... Hey.
It's not your fault.
I'm sorry.
You just need time.
You'll see.
Hey, good night.
- I love you.
- I love you, too.
Sydney? Can you see me?
Don't feel bad if you can't.
What's that on your head?
A bandana, my grandpa gave it to me.
You know, maybe tomorrow we can take
a walk and I can show you to park outside.
- Palm trees and...
- Alicia!
Oh. coming.
- Sasquatch, gotta go.
- Bye.
Please...
I don't want to go.
Mrs. Hellman?
Where're you taking her?
Oooh...
Mrs. Hellman?
Oooohh...
- Where're you taking her?
- Oh...
Yeaoohh!
Oh...
Freezing.
Freezing. Freezing. Freezing.
Where's Mrs. Hellman?
Oh, I'm sorry, she passed away last night.
Everything looks just perfect.
You're recovering quite nicely,
and the tearing has stopped?
- I think so... yeah.
- Good.
- Uhm... so, who's eyes were these?
- Excuse me?
My uh... my donor?
I'm afraid I can't help you with that, Sydney.
There’re your eyes now and they're working.
I shouldn't matter where they came from.
That hurt?
Yeah, a little.
When will I be able to see more clearly?
Well, it varies with each patient.
A couple of days, a couple weeks.
But your vision itself isn't the issue,
since you've been blind so long.
I'm going to refer you to a specialist.
Paul Faulkner, he helps you.
- You all right?
- Yeah.
- Alright, have a nice day off tomorrow.
- Thanks, Sydney. - OK.
Hi.
Hey.
Are you ready to be my tour guide?
You're leaving?
Yeah, I'm afraid they had enough of me here.
- This is my sister Helen, Helen, this is Alicia.
- Hi.
- Hey, can we get a picture together?
- Of course.
- I'll do it.
- Okay.
I know you're scared, Sydney.
Don't be.
The world it's... it's really beautiful.
Ok... smile.
My (?) is in the trunk, I just could
put it on your couch, you know, I could...
bring your meals, clean, and get
us in some art galleries.
Is it too much for you? I mean, you want me
to pull over or something? Just say the word.
No, no, no we can talk every day, you can
come over and check on me, I just...
I really think, I just need to do
something on my own, okay?
Okay, I understand.
- I got some new lambs for your place.
- Oh, thanks.
Just take a minute.
- Here, I'll do it.
- Okay.
Surprise.
- It's too soon, I know, I don't know what I was thinking.
- It's okay.
- Well, do I know any of you?
- Welcome home.
Oh, hi Jim.
How are you?
- Nice to see you.
- Nice to see you, too.
Sydney, it's Brett.
Welcome home.
- Hey, Sid, it's me, Alex from the upstairs.
- Hi.
- God, nice to see you.
- It's your cousin, Sarah.
- Oh, Sarah... it's been so long.
- I'm so happy.
- Recognize my voice?
- Hi, Cynthia.
- You knew it was me.
- How could I not, Cynthia.
Hello, girl.
- Oh, Richard, hi.
- How you're doing?
- So, this is what bald looks like.
- Mm'hm.
- Hey, Sydney. How are you?
- Miguel, how are you?
- You look good.
- Oh, honey thanks.
- Hello honey, how're you feeling?
- This is all so...
Take a breath.
Are you okay?
Do you need some water or anything?
Yeah, I'm gonna go to the kitchen.
Why don't you stay with the guest.
That's OK.
Oh, thank you guys for coming.
1:06 am.
- Hi.
Sorry, I'm late.
That's Henry.
- I'm Paul.
- Sydney.
Have a seat.
You damaged your cornea
when you were five?
Yeah, my sister and I were
playing with firecrackers.
I tried a transplant, when I was 12.
But I rejected them.
Uhm, 10/76, refused it then.
Have you tried again?
No, my sister was really the one
who kept up with all that stuff.
These are Dr. Haskin's test results, there's nothing
physically wrong with you, the operation went...
- flawlessly, but you're probably in for a shock.
- Why?
You've already felt the information
from sound, smell and touch.
But now, you're gonna be assaulting a million
things you never even knew existed.
It's a whole new level of confusion.
Gonna look here, see there... is that
bright thing important,
or this dark one, moving
toward me or away from me...
dangerous or not?
As long as your eyes are open,
there's just too many distractions,
I mean, how do you concentrate?
I'm talking to you and...
you're looking at that woman and
you're thinking, is she gonna eat that?
That's a pineapple, by the way, cut it open.
I like pineapple.
Sorry.
Anyway, because you can see, people gonna
expect you to do things, that you can't do.
Read signs, recognize body language, people's
gestures and facial expressions...
you just get out of their way,
your eyes will wanna dominate...
how you perceive the world,
but you can't fully trust them, not yet.
In the next few weeks, I'm gonna help
you to see the world like it really is, okay?
Some of it's gonna be wonderful, a lot of it's gonna
be difficult, but the main thing is, to be prepared.
And that's where I come in.
We're in this together.
You scared me.
Have you seen my report card?
Your report card?
- Do you live here, sweetie?
- My father will be so mad at me.
Have you seen my report card?
Sorry.
Let's take five.
I'm sorry, I don't know what's
wrong with me.
Relax.
You're pushing too hard.
You know, when I first went to London
to work with the Philharmonic...
I was so nervous, in Prague, I was a
big fish, in London, there were hundreds.
But you did very well in London.
I never thought I would be ready,
but when it was time to go on...
everything faded away,
it was just me.
Then there was nothing to worry about.
You know...
Sydney.
Will you be ready?
We're all counting on you.
- I'll be ready.
- I'm sure you'll be.
- 22.
- 22? That's us.
- You sit tide, I'll get it.
- Thank you.
- 22?
- Yea.
You think I'm just gonna let you go?
- You think, I'm not gonna do something?
- That's right!
- I'm gonna do it.
- I'm sorry.
I told you I was gonna do it.
That's all I got.
What's happened?
- There was a woman, she came at me.
- What woman?
What woman?
Christ, Sydney, get
a hold off yourself, please.
Sorry.
- I apologize.
- It's all right.
Witch! Witch! Witch!
- The ordinary scope from the spec analysis
- And that's good, right?
Well.
From the latest results, there's
nothing wrong with your eyes.
Well, maybe there's something
wrong with the tests.
The tests only gave us the fact,
that you gave them up normal responses.
Creative ones yes, like the kind
that artists and musicians give.
But last I checked, you are a musician.
I'm sure other musicians don't
see what I've been seeing.
Come with me.
I'm not an idiot.
I understand what you're telling me, my
brain's having to re-learn how to decode...
the world around it, but that's very different
for me seeing things, that don't seem to be real.
- How?
- Look, you're real, OK.
You're here.
My perspective and focus is off, but...
you're real, I can see you.
We see what we look at, but the way that
we see things, is the fact by what we know,
and there's a lot around you, that
can't make any sense to you.
What are you saying to me?
You think I'm making this up?
You think I want this to be happening to me?
You think you might not be able to push through this,
you think you were better before.
More special... well, you just discovered
that now you're like the rest of us.
You know when we first met,
I didn't think you were such an ass.
That's because you didn't
know how to spot one.
See?
Progress.
Have a good evening, Mrs. Charlene.
Ahh...
Ms. Wells, your new TV is here.
- My buddy from the cable co. hooked you up.
- Thank you Miguel.
And welcome to the 200 channel universe.
- Thanks, bye.
- Good night.
- I guess I should have known.
- You knew our history, when we got engaged
- I know but, it was just a kind of an experiment.
- If we've gotten only Jameson’s special kind of...
Hey, asshole...
Think they got it retail...
I'm spread out, a matter of fact...
Hi, this is Helen, I'm out of town till
Saturday, so if you need to contact me...
leave a message after the beep.
Hey, it's Sid.
Please call me.
Hey, what're you doing?
She's not breading, is she?
Hi, you've reached the
cell phone of Dr Paul Faulkner.
Leave a message after the beep.
Hey, Paul, it's Sydney.
I... I'm at a Chinese restaurant on
the corner of 4th. and Figaro.
Something's happening to me.
I need you to come, please.
Excuse me.
Sydney, Sydney, it's me, it's me.
It's me.
This place.
- I was just here, I was here.
- What're you talking about?
- This place...
There was a fire in here...
There was a fire in here, weeks ago, 5 people were killed,
it was in the paper, it was all over the press.
I was here, I was just here.
What is this place?
- What's wrong?
- Everything is wrong.
Everything is wrong, my apartment keeps
changing, it was filled with smoke and...
- I... I was attacked by this man.
- What do you mean "attacked"?
He was on fire and then he was gone, everything
was gone, so I had to get outta there.
And then I was walking down the street and
this woman walks through me.
She walked right through me.
and then I saw the shadow.
I saw it before, at the hospital,
it's... it's some kind of an escort...
that takes people away when
they're dead.
There's something so angry about them.
They don't wanna be seen.
And then this, I see people,
like nothing's wrong.
but they don't seem to see me.
Sydney, listen to me.
I'm seeing things that aren't real.
I'm seeing things that I shouldn't see.
I'm dreaming things that I've never seen.
This surgery was supposed to
make me normal.
Sydney, your eyes are not the problem.
These eyes are not my eyes.
- Yes they are.
- No they aren't.
Yes they are.
- Yes they are.
Listen to me.
You have got a disorder.
We've gotta teach your brain how to...
separate out this ghost images
from the real thing.
You're not listening to me.
I'm not seeing ghost images.
I see...
What, dead people?
Rooms that change, phantom escorts.
Whatever it is...
that you believe you're seeing is not real.
It's not.
It's not real.
You don't believe me.
I wanna help you.
How can you?
How can you if you don't believe me?
You're gettin' on or what?
It's not real.
No no, It's not real.
It's not real. It's not real.
Have you seen my report card?
- Have you seen my report card?
- No... I've already told you.
- Stop asking me.
No.
Have you seen my report card?
It's Helen. I'm on my way to the airport.
Are you okay?
Will you call me?
I'm on my cell, okay? Please.
You're scaring me. Sweetie, pick up.
OK, I'm gonna call someone... I'm gonna call
someone unless you pick up, Sydney.
Sydney?
- Miss Wells.
- Sydney.
- Paul, you're in there?
- Why don't you let me in, all right?
Miss Wells.
Can you give us a minute?
Sure.
Your sister called, she said you
haven't answered the phone in days.
What's this? You wanna be blind again? At least
you were right, when you were blind, you had a life,
you were engaged in the world,
you had a job. But, what is this?
You get scared, you just drop out,
run back to your room, turn off your lights?
So what now?
I'm gonna take you to the hospital
and get these cuts sewn up.
- Is that really necessary?
- Yeah.
Then we're gonna figure this out.
I think we should just keep her here
all night. Here's my number, just in case.
Sydney Wells?
You're back.
Alicia.
What're you doing here?
My golf ball’s are gone, Sydney Wells.
- What?
- I have to go now.
Wait, hang on...
Alicia.
Alicia?
They know you're scared. Don't be.
Because the world is really beautiful.
No, Alicia.
Don't go with him!
Alicia.
How are you?
Whatever is happening,
there is nothing that can't be fixed.
Good Morning.
- How is your hand?
- It's fine.
Alicia's mother wanted you to have this.
She said, she talked about you all the time,
she was smiling up to the very end.
Who is she?
- That's you, Sydney.
- That's not me.
Of course it is.
Who else would it be?
What're you doing?
Sydney.
- You're scaring me.
- What do you see?
Cellular memory based on the theory that all
living tissues have the capacity to remember...
cellular memory explains how energy
and information from...
a donor's tissue can transfer, consciously
or unconsciously, to the recipient
Recently, recipients of organ transplants have
begun to report episodes of new found memories.
Thoughts, emotions and characteristics
that are often associated to the original donor.
Paul!
Sydney, I can't talk right now,
I gotta go to for an interview.
Listen, there is no history of schizophrenia in my
family, I have never suffered any mental condition.
No depression, migraines, nothing, so for
argument's sake, let's just pretend I'm not crazy.
All right, walk with me.
There have been cases of transplants...
who've actually shown characteristics of the donor.
- That's cellular memory.
- Yeah.
There was a liver transplantation
in Kentucky last year.
She almost immediately felt the urgency to
take up smoking and she hadn't her entire life.
- Her donor was a chain smoker?
- Down to the same brand.
And a few years ago, this little girl helped the
police solve the murder of the person...
she got her heart from, she kept
having visions of the crime.
- There's some kind of a chemical, it's uh...
- Peptides, that's how the mind and body communicate.
So it's not too far off to suggest that memories
can also be accessed from these organs too.
No, because corneas aren't a major organ,
It's like changing the windshield on a car.
But there is still a chance, isn't there?
I need it...
I need that chance.
I need to find out who the donor was,
I see her in the mirror every day.
I have to find out who she was.
That is confidential information,
You can't ask me to do that.
I could lose my license.
Your license?...
Well, by all means, hold on to that license.
Sydney, let's go.
Sydney, come on.
Thank you.
- What floor?
- 14.
Excuse me.
Sorry.
Thank you.
He's here, isn't he.
My Tommy.
What was that about?
Who's Tommy?
Her son.
Where was he?
He's dead.
Who are you?
What do you want?
I wanna help you.
But how can I, if you won't even tell me.
Sydney.
Are you okay?
Sydney, open up.
Open up.
What the hell is going on?
- I need to find out who she is.
- Who?
My donor, her eyes... are my eyes.
I'm seeing what she saw.
I'm seeing what killed her.
- Sydney, please.
- Helen, don't.
I love you, but there's no way
you can help me.
You're not making any sense.
It's all happening to me, everything that
happened to her is happening to me.
Until I find out who she is and what she wants,
it's gonna keep happening.
To the center please.
Hey.
The only cornea transplant that matches
the day of your surgery came from...
Clínica De Santa Haviera Mosianos.
Your donor was from Mexico.
Do you get car sick?
- Why?
- It's a 15 hour drive.
Thank you.
The file says that your donor was
Ana Christina Martinez.
One living relative, mother, worked in a
ceramics factory.
Hopefully we can track her down.
- So, what made you change your mind?
- About what?
About coming down here with me?
What don't you just let me sabotage
my career in peace?
I'm just wondering why you've changed your
mind, that's all. Was it because you believe me?
Paul, stop the car.
What'd you see?
There was a fire here.
I keep seeing fire.
Maybe they know something.
- Hello, boy
- Hello.
What happened over there?
When the fire started, everybody was
locked inside, nobody got out,
All the doors were locked and
nobody could get out.
My brother died there.
He lost a brother.
- How did it happen?
- How it happened, the fire?
The Witch did it, it's all her fault.
He says something about the witch.
- Come on, let's go...
- I'm going, won't talk alone.
Can't we talk alone?
Let's talk alone... tell me!
You see that?
"Bruta".
Yea, I've seen it before.
What does it mean?
It means Witch.
I don't think anyone is here.
Hello! Is anyone here?... Hello!
- Hello.
- Hello, Senor Martinez?
No, I work here.
Is someone from the Martinez family here
that we can speak to?
Senora Martinez is here, but she is resting.
Well, we can wait.
It's important.
Emilio! It's okay.
Come in.
Please don't be long.
She is not well.
Mrs. Martinez, my name is Sydney Wells and
this is my friend Dr. Paul Faulkner.
What do you want?
We would like to talk about your daughter.
I was wondering about how she died.
What business is this of yours?
It's hard to explain.
I have a connection... with your daughter.
Oh, dear God...
You have her eyes.
I'm sorry for how I look. There was a fire
in the factory where I worked.
- Did your daughter die in the fire?
- No, but many other did.
If they had listened to Ana,
they would have been saved.
- What do you mean by that?
- It doesn't matter now.
Did Ana ever...
...see things she couldn't explain?
Do you see things?
- Things that are not real?
- Yeah.
It's a terrible thing,
to see the spiritual world, isn't it?
To see souls destined to repeat death
every day and unable to find peace?
Yeah.
Ana was always alone.
People around here were always afraid of her.
- They would blame her.
- Why would they blame her?
Sometimes when she was a little girl...
she would sit in front of the person's house,
and she would just cry.
And soon after, somebody
in that house would die.
I know that she wasn't doing these things,
she wasn't bringing death to anyone, but...
...she just could see death.
This is a small town with many superstitious
As I know as anything
better to do all that...
- Call an ambulance.
- What?
Call an ambulance.
Every night...
She does it again and again.
Please save her.
Save her.
What happened?
She's having a heart attack.
We gotta get her to the hospital.
- Please, can you get her?
- Got her.
Where're your keys?
In my right hand pocket.
Hey, open the door.
Alright bring her in, head in first.
Go on the other side.
Put her in, head first.
Can you hold her legs for me?
- Got it.
- Have you almost there.
All right, close the door, close the door.
Hurry up.
Get the keys, you drive.
You know the way.
Hurry up.
Come on... come on.
- I need to stay here.
- What?
I'm fine.
Just go.
I'll be quick.
Don't go anywhere.
All right, Ana.
I'm here.
What do you want me to see?
- My Mom!...
- Shut up Witch.
- Where's my Mom?
- Get out’ a here!
- Get out!
- Please, where is my Mother?
- Get out, she's not here.
- I wanna see my Mom.
- Do I have to throw you out?
- No, no, no... Mommy!
- Come, help me get her out.
- Get out.
- No, Mama! Mama!
- What's going on?
- Nothing, go do your job!
- Who was here?
- Nobody was here, go back to work!
What's everybody staring at? Back to
work. Understand! Get back to work!
Fire!
Oh, my God, Help me!
Mama? Mama?
Witch! Witch! Witch!
Hello?
Paul, is that you?
Forgive me.
Ana?
I have to do this, forgive me.
Ana, no!
No!
Help me?
Stop.
Please.
God.
No, no! No, no, no!
Come on, come on.
What am I supposed to do?
Please, tell me?
Your mother asked me to save you,
but I don't know how.
What am I supposed to do?
I don't know what to do here.
What?
What do you want from me?
Tell me.
Help, please.
I did try to warn them.
I believe you.
I see what you saw. I know what
you've been through. I believe you.
I tried to help and save them.
It was never your fault.
How is Mrs. Martinez?
She didn't make it.
Thank you.
Hey, buddy.
What is going on?
Some high speed chase on the American
side has the whole border shut down.
Nearly an hour now.
You might as well make yourself comfortable.
Great.
Thanks.
- How long was I out?
- Not very long.
It's freezing.
What's going on?
There's some kind of chase on the other side
of the border, that's why we're being held up.
Really?
You wanna play a game?
Mommy?
What're doing? Get back in the car.
- Come on, you're scaring the little girl, let's go.
- Wait.
What... you're scaring the hell
out of her, get back in the car!
What?
Oh, God!
Sydney!
Sydney! Sydney!
Sorry about that.
You're alright? Sorry.
I see the Shadows.
They're everywhere.
Excuse! Excuse me, please.
Open up. Open up, please.
Listen, there's gonna be an accident.
We don't have a lot of time.
Please, just let me to talk to
the driver. Okay? Please!
Miss, what're you doing?
Oh my God.
Don't you understand?
That's what she wanted me to see.
Everything I dreamt wasn't from
Ana Christina's life. It was from this.
Right now.
She let me see that this was gonna
happen, so I wouldn't end up like her.
She wants me to save these people.
That's what she wants me to do.
- Sydney.
- You have to believe me.
You have to believe me.
You need to get off this bus.
Everyone needs to get off this bus.
All of you...
You can't stay here.
Everyone listen to me, you have to get off
this bus, you have to get off this bus, right now!
- Is it like a terrorist thing?
- Yes.
That's exactly what it's.
There's a bomb on the bus.
- There is a bomb, a bomb.
- Quickly.
Get out.
Come on.
Get out of the car.
Everyone.
Come on. Come on.
Get away from here.
There is a bomb in the bus.
Come on. Come on.
Get out.
- Go, go, go.
- Bomb, bomb, bomb.
Come on. Come on.
Get out of your car.
Wait here, sweetie.
- What's going on?
- Get out of your car.
Mom.
Come on. Come on.
Get those people out of here.
Get out of your car.
Mommy!
- You all right?
- Get my daughter, she is inside.
- Open the door.
- How? Please.
Please, help me..
Help.
Stay back.
I'm gonna break the window.
Close your eyes.
Come here, honey.
Paul, let's go.
Hurry up!
- Come on, come on.
- Mom!
You saved them, Sydney.
You saved them.
Some say, seeing is believing.
Now I know what they mean.
Ana Christina tried to prevent death.
But she was ultimately powerless
to stop it.
Ana and I sure both have
a blessing and a curse.
I know now, I don't need eyes to
see what truly matters.
The gift of Ana's sight lead me
to see what I was afraid of...
to use that vision,
to not only save myself and others...
but to give Ana the peace she
never found in life.
FiNAL EDiT BY
~|~ N3krA ~|~
www.subs4u.gr $ www.stizoula.com